What's going on everybody? How are we
doing today? Welcome to another video.
Today I'm going to be showing you guys
my workflow that uses a reference image.
As you can see here, any image that you
want you can use as a reference.
Passes it through a few nodes and then
gives us an output based on that
reference image with any changes that we
are wanting to make. So, I am using
a RTX 4090 through RunPod for this
example. You may be able to use
something that's a little outdated, more
outdated than the RTX 4090. But, for
example purposes I'm going to be using
the 4090 today.
Just a quick side note, if you haven't
used ComfyUI yet, I have a video on how
to launch ComfyUI through RunPod for the
very first time. And if you're using
RunPod for this and you have not added
credits to your account with a min
minimum purchase of
$10,
my referral link is in the description.
That will get you an extra $5 with that
first minimum purchase of 10.
So,
please use that. It's free money for you
and free money for me.
So, back to the workflow.
I'm going to quickly run through and
explain each node to you guys so that
you understand how the workflow works.
But, first I just want to point out that
if you do not have the segment anything
or SAM model installed,
which is this model right here, there
will be an install command that you can
run through your Jupyter Labs in the
description. So,
what you're going to do is take that
command that is in the description, open
up a new terminal in your Jupyter Labs.
Make sure that you aren't trying to put
this into your terminal in which you
have launched ComfyUI. You're just going
to click the plus button up here and
create a new terminal.
Terminal down here and you're going to
paste that
command with all of the
models that you'll need to install. It's
pretty lightweight. The models are very
small, so won't take long at all. So,
yeah, we have the SAM model here. We
have the the BBox face detector and we
have the BBox eye detector,
which are used to detail the face and
detail the eyes.
So, running through the nodes real quick
just to give you guys a base explanation
on how the workflow works. I'm using Z
Image Turbo for this example, but you
may be able to use other models. Just
make sure that you guys are changing
things like the clip and the VAE so that
they are compatible with whatever base
model you decide to use.
So, first we load our base models.
And then we're going to load in our
reference image, which I'm going to
choose real quick.
So, I'm going to drag my
reference image, which I just found on
Pinterest. Pinterest is a great source
for a lot of images that you can use for
reference if you are doing something
like creating an AI influencer or
something like that. Lot of images on
there.
So, I load in that reference image and
then we're going to pass that reference
image through a resolution upscale based
on your desired dimensions. So, I'm
going to be using 1280 here because
it's kind of in the middle of low
quality and high quality and gives me
good results, so that's what I'm going
to use. Then we're going to pass that
upscaled image through a VAE encoder,
which is right here.
And then take that latent output after
encoding through a Clown Shark sampler,
which is just a K sampler, but it has a
few more options. It's a bit more
customizable. I recommend that you use
this. Install the missing custom nodes
that you don't have. If you need it,
you'll get it installed just by doing
that. And then we're going to load our
chosen Laura,
which I'm going to pick here.
So, I just picked the Laura that I want
to use, which is one of the characters
that I've created. Just a quick side
note, you don't need to load a Laura,
but you will get really good results if
you do. So, I recommend training a
Laura. I have a video on that in my on
my profile, so go check that out. Now,
the last step before generating our
image is going to be coming over to the
positive and negative prompting section.
Z Image Turbo does not use negative
prompting at all, so I just have a
negative prompt at zero out here. That's
what this node will do. If you use a
different model, you're going to have to
replace this with a negative prompt node
or just a text box node. So, make sure
you do that if you're using a different
model, but if you're using Z Image
Turbo, you can just ignore it. Now,
positive prompting, you're going to want
to use your Laura keyword and describe
certain features that might get
overwritten by the qualities in the
reference image that you're using. So,
eye color and hair color the biggest
thing that's going to get over written
or the influence from the reference
image is going to be strong enough to
just bleed through your character Laura
and give you
features that don't look like your
character.
So, everything will then be compiled
into the Clown Shark sampler. It'll
generate an image and
you're going to see here that we have
assuming that you installed the face
detection, eye detection, and segment
anything or SAM models, our image will
now run through these two post
refinement nodes. The first being face
detailing, which will give us better
facial features such as skin quality and
texture, eyelash and brow realism, lip
texture, and natural imperfections like
wrinkles, dimples, scars, and hair
follicles. Next, we take the detailed
face and pass it again through a similar
detailing node. This one being the eye
detailer, which will enhance and fix the
eyes, give us better quality such as
pupil size, glare from lighting,
wrinkles under the eyes, eyelid texture,
and so on. So, let's run a few
generations and using a few different
reference images, I'm going to show you
guys the results.
While this is running, I just wanted to
point this out real quick. Changing the
steps if you want higher or lower step
count in the in the Clown Shark sampler
is not it's not going to do anything
because we have this beta sampling
scheduler. So, all the steps that
are going to be passed through the Clown
Shark sampler are going to be through
this. So, if you want to change the
steps, change it here, not in the Clown
Shark sampler. It won't do anything. All
right. So, we got
our first result. This looks exactly
like the character Laura that I'm using.
Looks great. I'm going to get a few more
reference images to run through.
Uh real quick, I just want to compare
these. So,
you can see that for the most part we
have pretty similar looking images from
our reference image. You know, we got
the drape in the background, the beige
drape. Um we got the couch.
One thing that you should note as well
is that if you are wanting
to get more likeness from your
character, say that your character is
not being output as desired in your in
your output images from the reference,
you can change the denoise value in the
Clown Shark sampler. You can change this
up to about 0.9 is the highest that I
would go because if you change this to
1.0, then it will completely reimagine
the image. It won't even use the
reference image at all. So, you
definitely don't want to put this at
one. Now, if your character Laura is
overriding the reference image a little
bit too much, you can turn this denoise
value down. You can mess with it, kind
of configure it, whatever works best for
you. Change it a little bit if you're
not getting the results that you want,
but 0.8 is perfect for me. So, I'm going
to leave it at that.
All right. So, for the second
generation, I picked a purposely looking
AI picture to show you how well the face
detailer and the eye detailer and the
Clown Shark sampler do at just upping
the realism. I also picked a picture
that kind of has the face a little bit
closer up so you can really see the
detail here. So, here's our reference
image and here's our output.
It looks great. Looks absolutely
amazing, actually. And I'm going to find
one more reference image to run through
here to give you guys another example.
So, for this generation again, I picked
a pretty AI looking image. You can see
here the eyes look [__] up. Face is
like really smooth. Even the mountains
kind of look AI. So, I purposely and the
trees too, actually. Just noticing. So,
I purposely picked something like that,
ran it through the workflow, and here we
go. Here's our result.
Face looks great. The eye looks a little
bit weird, but that's what you can
probably expect when you use something
that's as [__] up as this.
But, the trees in the background look
way more real. Even the mountains look
more real. The ground looks more real,
but focus being on the character here,
it looks great. Doesn't have that smooth
plastic looking AI skin texture and it
displays our character perfectly. So,
this workflow is going to be available
in my Discord. The link to that will be
in the descriptions and pinned in the
comment section. So, just head over to
the Discord, go to the free workflow
section and you'll you'll be able to
find it there. It's completely free.
Thank you for watching, guys.